Guide to the Himalayan Collection Pamphlets and Reports
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Classified Materials, Series I
  - L: Nepali Diaspora
    - Bibliographies, c. 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Biography of Christianity in Nepal and the Himalayas (with separate sections on Bhutan, Sikkim, the Nepali Bible and Hymn Books, and Archival Sources) by Cindy Perry (c.1995)
    - Protestant History, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      The History of the Expansion of Protestant Christianity Among the Nepali Diaspora, volumes I and II by Cindy L. Perry (1994)
  - M: Church in Nepal
    This section contains English books, surveys, etc. [See also Church collection]
    - History of Nepal, 1953-2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Titles: Inside Nepal by Christa Shanti Sangh (1953); Nepal extract from World Christian Encyclopedia (2001); Nepal extract from World Christian Encyclopedia (1982); Nepal extract from The Church in Asia by Samuel R. Burgoyne and Jonathan Lindell (1975)
    - Christianity in Nepal - 1, 1962-1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Titles: We Confess Jesus Christ is Lord by Church of Christ in Nepal (1962) - 2 copies; A Brief Survey of Christianity in Nepal by Gopaljee Adhikari (c.1981); How Christianity Came to Nepal by Beth Allinger (n.d.); The Church in Nepal by Julia Coburn and Corry Nap (1993); Ramghat Church, Pokhara, Nepal by Paul Kaltoff (c.1985)
    - Christianity in Nepal - 2, 1984, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Tites: The Church History of Nepal with Special Reference to Assemblies of God by Narayan Sharma (1984); A Biographical History of the Church in Nepal by Cindy Perry (1989) - 2 copies
    - Christianity in Nepal - 3, 1987, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Titles: Contemporary Nepalese Christianity by Jan MInderhoud (1987); Asian Church Today, v.8 no.3 by Evangelical Fellowship of Asia (1991); The Free Church of Finland HImalayan Mission and the Nepalese (n.d.)
    - Church Growth, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Titles: A Study on Equipping Laity for Church Growth by Mangal Man Maharjan (1989)
    - Missions in Nepal, 1992-1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Titles: Para-Church and Other Missions in Nepal: Mission Organisations in Nepal by Julia Coburn (1992); 'Souvenir' A Decade of Baptist Mission in Nepal by Sumi Baptist Church (1995); Strongholds of the 10/40 Window: National Mini-Profiles for Intercessors by The Sentinel Group (1993); Spiritual Mapping Field Guide: North American Edition by The Sentinel Group (1993)
    - Human Rights materials, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Titles: Nepal: A Pattern of Human Rights Violations by Amnesty International (1987); Amnesty International Information Catalogue: Nepal (1990); Nepal Jubilee Campaign Guide to Prayer Action: Christians are Fined, Beaten, Tortured, and Imprisoned in the World's Only Hindu Kingdom of Nepal (c.1990); Communication under ECOSOC Resolution 1503 by Evangelical Fellowship of Asia (c.1990)
    - Global Prayer Digest, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Titles: Frontier Fellowship Global Prayer Digest v.13 n.5 (1994); Frontier Fellowship Global Prayer Digest v.14 n.7 (1995)
    - Hindu/Christian Relations - 1, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Titles: A Christian Approach to Hinduism in Nepal by Bala Krishna Sharma (1981)
    - Hindu/Christian Relations - 2, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Titles: A Comparative Study of Hindu and Biblical Concept of Salvation with Special Reference to the Strategy to Evangelize Hindus in Nepal by Mangal Man Maharjan (1989)
    - Materials in Nepali, 1990-2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Titles: The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri (in Nepali) by Norma Kehrberg (2000); Two Nepali pamphlets (c.1990); Barnabas Rai - handwritten testimony in Nepali by Barnabas Rai (c.1990); Nepali item, apparent souvenir of the funeral of Mary S. Karthak by Gyaneshwor Church (c.2000)
    - Nepalese Books, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Titles: Two books in Nepalese.
  - P: General
    Overall description, geography, etc.
    - Autobiographical history, c.1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Titles: From the Snows of Kathmandu to the Sands by Juanita Owen Fleming (c.1990) - first three chapters only
    - Maps and Illustrations, 1966-1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Titles: Nepal in Maps by Ministry of Information and Broadcasting (1966); Ancient Nepal: A Picture Book by Bernhard Milcke (1978)
  - Q: History and Politics
    - "The Records" Weekly Newsletter, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      8 booklets of "The Records" weekly newsletter from 1992: Vol. 1 No. 2; Vol. 1 No. 4; Vol. 1 No. 5; Vol. 1 No. 9; Vol. 1 No. 10; Vol. 1 No. 12; Vol. 1 No. 15; Vol. 1 No. 17; Vol. 1 No. 18 & 19
    - General History, 1965-1995 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Titles: Six Months in Nepal by Shriman Narayan (1965); photocopied excerpts of Nepal by Perceval Landon (1976); Episode of the Naga Tragedy by Rev. Dr. V. K. Nuh (1995)
    - Church Material, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Titles: Presbysterian Review Vol. II No. 8 by The Presbyterian Church of India (1996)
    - Politics and Political History, 1963-1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Titles: Three Stars & Ten Principles by Purna Bahadur Manab (n.d.); King Mahendra's Bold Step by Purna Bahadur Manab (1963); King Mahendra's National Stand by Purna Bahadur Manab (1960); Humanaised Socialism Vol. 1-3 by Purna Bahadur Manab (n.d.); Campaign for Peace by Ihezhe Sema (n.d.); Social Service National Co-ordination Council Act, 1977 (As Amended by the Social SErvice National Co-ordination Council [First Amendement] Act, 1982) (1982); Panchayat System in Nepal by Narayan Prasad Uprety (n.d.); The Pro-Democracy movement in Nepal 1947-1990: An Analysis of Non-Violent Change by W. Jean Hirschler (1991); Assorted copies of articles regarding Nepalese political history
    - Nepalese Booklets, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 5)
      1 Nepalese booklet with an orange cover
    - Newspaper and Website Articles - 1, 1990-2004 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Large folder with assorted articles clipped from newspapers and printed from the internet. They all pertain to politics in Nepal.
    - Newspaper and Website Articles - 2, 1985-2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      More assorted newspaper articles and articles printed from the internet about Nepal. Some pertain to politics, but this folder also has some related to environmental and cultural topics. Some of the articles include: The Kathmandu Valley: Earthquake Risk Management Action Plan (1999); Analyzation of Nepali Music by M. Thoresen Tansen
  - R: Culture, Including religion tribes
    - Articles Regarding Religion and Human Ecology, 1867-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Titles: References to Buddhism in the Nepalamahatmya by Horst Brinkhaus (1980); Regional Circles and the Central Overseer of the Vaishnavite Sects in the Kingdom of Nepal by Richard Burghart (1984); Ascetics in Western Nepal by Patricia Caplan (1973); The Divali, the Lamp Festival of the Hindus by W. Crooke (1923); The Lepcha People and Their Notions of Heaven and Hell by Kali Kumar Das (1896); Harmonizing Dimension in Hindu Civilizational Processes by S. C. Dube (1983); Introduction: Human Ecology in the Himalaya by Thomas Fricke (1989); Nepal (Kingdom of Nepal) ed. by Robin Morgan (1984); The Limbu or Kiranti People of Eastern Nepal and Sikkim by Kali Kumar Das (1896); Recent Works on Shamanism, A Review ARticle by Mircea Eliade (n.d.); Miscellanea Divali-Folklore by B. A. Gupte (1903); A Nepalese Shamanism and the Classic Inner Asian Tradition by John T. Hitchcock (1967); Preliminary Report on a Field Research in a Western Tamang Group, Nepal by Andras Hoefer (1969); Religious Belief and Development: A Christian Approach to Development Among Animistic/Shamanistic Peoples (with special reference to North Western Nepal (Jumla)) by John Studley (1992); Ecological Change and Adaptation Among the Gurungs by Donald A. Messerschmidt (1976)
    - Miscellaneous Religion Materials, c.a. 1980-2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      This folder contains assorted materials regarding religion in Nepal, with a particular focus on Christianity. The contents are primarily newspaper articles and articles printed from the internet, but it also includes handwritten notes and a few slim booklets. Some of the materials are in Nepalese, but most are in English. Titles include, but are not limited to... The Festivals of Nepal by Nepal's Ministry of Tourism; U.K. Christian Centre for Buddhist Studies pamphlet; Hinduism: The Religion of India by The Quiet Miracle magazine (1986); Traditional Health Beliefs and Healing Practices in Nepal
    - Migration Materials, 1951-1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      These materials primarily relate to India. Titles: On International Migration and International Relations by Myron Weiner (1985); Immigration: The Foreign Trickle by Davis (1951); Assorted copied pages from The population of India and Pakistan by Davis (1951); Assorted handwritten pages Indian Census Centenary Seminar: Summaries of Papers & Proceedings in Delhi - Internal Migration Moderator's Statement by Sidney Goldstein (1972)
    - Nepalese Society Materials, 1934-1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      This folder contains materials regarding Nepalese society. In particular, articles relate to ethinic and tribal groups, languages of these groups, and Nepalese women in their society. The materials are all copied articles and handwritten notes. Titles include but are not limited to... Working in a Multi Religious and Multi Cultural Society by Rita Rudra; Legal Position of Nepalese Women in Family by Silu Singh; Nepalese Women by Indra Majupuria (1982); Lepcha Marriage Customs (1934); Prayer for Nepal (1985); Ethnographic Notes on the Tamangs of Nepal by Christoph von Furer-Haimendorf (1956); Preliminary Report on a Field Research in a Western Tamang Group, Nepal by Andras Hofer; Notes on the Language of Gurung Pe by S. S. Strickland (1987); Status and Interaction among the High Hindu Castes of Nepal by Christoph von Furer-Haimendorf (1971)
    - Articles regarding Nepal, 1956-1991 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      Titles: Sanskritization in Eastern Nepal by Rex L. Jones (1976); Hinduization of a Himalayan Tribe in Nepal by Shigeru Iijima (1963); Ritual Brotherhood: A Cohesive Factor in Nepalese Society by Ferdinand E. Okada (1957); Cultural Politics: Religious Activism and Ideological Transformation Among 20th Century Sherpas by Sherry B. Ortner (1989); Ethnographic Notes on the Tamangs of Nepal by Christoph von Fuerer-Haimendorf (1956); Dasain and Tihar: The Two Great Festivals of Nepalese by Deepkar Rajbhandari (1991)
  - S: Government and State of Nepal
    - Nepal in Figures, 1988-1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Pamphlets entitled "Nepal in Figures" from 1988, 1992, 1994, and 1996, printed by the Central Bureau of Statistics of Nepal.
    - Nepal Census, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Census of Population: Nepal 1952-1954 A.D. by the Department of Statistics in Kathmandu, Nepal (1958)
    - Materials in Nepalese, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Three books written in Nepalese.
    - Statistical Pocket Books, 1974-1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      This folder contains 5 books entitled "Statistical Pocket Book: Nepal" published by the Central Bureau of Statistics in Nepal in the years 1974, 1982, 1988, 1990, and 1994.
    - Constitution of Nepal, 1959-1990 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      This folder contains three publications of the Constitutuion of Nepal. Titles: The Constitution of the Kingdom of Nepal by Nepal Trading Corporation (1959); The Constitution of Nepal (as amended on January 27, 1967 by the First Amendment of the Constitution) by His Majesty's Government of Nepal Ministry of Law and Justice (1967); Constitution of the Kingdom of Nepal 2047 and Electoral Laws by Legal Research ASsociates (1990)
    - Offical Plans for Nepal, 1962-1991 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Titles: His Majesty's Government Three Year Plan 1962-65 Summary (1962); Nepal The Fifth Plan (1975-80) In Brief by the National Planning Commission His Majesty's Government Nepal (1975); Basic Principles of The Seventh Plan (1985-1990) by His Majesty's Government National Planning Commission Kathmandu (March, 1984); Approach to The Eighth Plan 1992-97 by His Majesty's Government National Planning Commission Nepal (November, 1991)
    - Miscellaneous, 1982-1993 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Titles: Nepal: Human RIghts in the HImalayas by Nepal National Coordination Committee for the United Nations World Conference on Human Rights (June 1993); Diplomatic List: List of the Diplomatic Corps and the Royal Nepalese Missions abroad by Protocol Division Ministry of Foreign Affairs HIs Majesty's Government of Nepal, Kathmandu (January 1990); Industrial Policy & Act of His Majesty's Government of Nepal (1987); The Nepalese Elite by Centre for the Study of Nepal Department of Political Science Banaras Hindu University (1982)
    - Kathmandu Valley Plan, 1969 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
      The Physical Development Plan for the Kathmandu Valley by His Majesty's Government of Nepal Department of Housing and Physical Planning, Ministry of Public Works Transport and Communications (June, 1969)
  - T: Development - General
    - Social Service National Co-Ordination Council, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Titles: Inventory of INGO's in Collaboration with SSNCC by Social Service National Co-Ordination, Council Training, Research, and Publication Division (1989)
    - Private Agencies Collaboration Together (PACT), 1987 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Titles: Final Report: The Non-Governmental Organization Sector of Nepal: NGO Functions and Capacities, Needs and Potentials for Strategic Gains in Development, Recommended Strategy for NGO Institutional and Program Support by a PACT Team for USAID, Nepal including Jacob E. Pfohl, Khrisna Sob, and Raju Joshi (April, 1987)
    - Nepal Atlas, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Development Atlas of Nepal (National, Regional, Zonal and District): Statistical Profile by Centre for Research Team (Anusandhan Toli Kendra) (August, 1988)
  - V: Development - Education
    - Nepal National Education, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Titles: National Education System Plan for 1971-76 by Ministry of Education His Majesty's Government of Nepal (1971)
  - W: Development - Health
    - Project Formulation - 1, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Basic Health Services Project Formulation (1975) - reports and drafts These materials contain reports from various subgroups and other documents related to the Basic Health Services project.
    - Project Formulation - 2, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Titles: Project Formulation for Basic Health Services Final Draft (July 1975 - January 1976)
  - X: Journals, Magazines, Newspapers
    - Magazines, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Titles: The Rising Nepal: Coronation Special edited by Barun Shamsher Rana and published by The Gorkhapatra Snasthan (February 24, 1975)
  - Y: Miscellaneous
    - Dictionaries, 1923 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Titles: English-Nepali Dictionary From Material Collected by the Rev. R. Kilgour, revised and arranged by the Rev. H. C. Duncan, with the assistance of the REv. G. P. Pradhan, and published by Darjeeling Government Branch Press (1923)
- Addendum, Series II
  - Bhutan Materials
    - History and General Information, n.d. - 2003 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Titles: People Groups and Languages of Bhutan (n.d.); Echoes of Ancient Ethos: Reflections on Some Popular Bhutanese Social Themes by Karma Phuntsho (2003); A Rough Translation of: A Summary of An Account of Mongar Dzongkhag, First Draft by Dasho Lam Sangha (n.d.)
    - Education, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Titles: The Alpha Course (n.d.)
  - Mongolia
    - Women, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Titles: Non-Formal Education to Meet Basic Learning Needs of Nomadic Women in the Gobi Desert - Mongolia (June, 1991)
  - Tibet Materials
    - Buddhists, 1993-2006 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Titles: Tibetan Buddhist Peoples in Russia by the Swedish Slavic Mission (January, 1993); Perspectives on the World Christian Movement: Unreached People Group Project: Tibetan: Amdo by Rebecca Garreau and Dan Johnson (2002); Ministry to Tibetan Buddhists in Goal, The Annual Magazine of InterServe/USA (1996); Index of Tibetan Buddhist Peoples by Marku Tsering (n.d.); Booklet in a Slavic language with English subtitles in the table of contents referencing Tibetan Buddhists
    - Calendars, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Titles: Tibetan Hearts calendar (2004); Pray for Tibet That they may Know calendar (2004)
    - Education - 1 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Titles: The Way of Hope: The Gospel according to St. Mark, published by The Bible Society of India (n.d.); "In the Beginning..." - a course in Tibetan about the book of Genesis (n.d.); Educational book in the native language for children
    - Education - 2, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Titles: Firm Foundations Volumes 1 and 2 by Trevor Mcillwin and Nancy Everson (n.d.)
    - Evangelism Materials, 1967-2001 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Titles: Some Ideas for Meaningful Conversations by G. Bailey (2001); Developing a Prayer Strategy - A DAWN Resource for the Twenty-First Century by DAWN (c.a. 2000); Mobilize Your Church for Tibetan Peoples: A practical guide...with the resources to do it (n.d.); In Search of a Relevant Tibetan Gospel and a VIable TIbetan Church (1998); The Religion of Tibet and the True Religion for English-Speaking Tibetans by Fredrik Franson (1967)
    - General History and Information, 1977-2003 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Titles: Cultural Relations on th eKansu-Tibetan Border (1977); Book with 2 chapters by David Woodward (n.d.); Glimpses of the History of the rGya Clan with Reference to the Nyang stod, IHo Mon and Nearby Lands (7th-13th century) by Roberto Vitali (n.d.); Qiangic Speaking Tibetans (n.d.); Qiangic Speaking Tibetans (n.d.); Direct Seeding and Transplanting by Kunde Foundation, Shannan Health Bureau (2002); Use Litter to Grow Vegetables by Kunde Foundation (2002); The Harvest and Preparation of Vegetables for Food by Kunde Foundation (n.d.); Sowing Information of Vegetable Seeds by Dawa and the Kunde Foundation (n.d.); Food Garden by Kunde Foundation (n.d.); Agriculture Training Materials by Kunde Foundation (2002); Seed Saving by Kunde Foundation (2003)
    - Health, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Titles: The Good Health Handbook (n.d.); TB: A Global Emergency (n.d.) - 2 copies; How to take a Medical History in Tibetan - Chinese (n.d.) Various printed materials with information regarding different diseases in the native language. These diseases include AIDS, HIV, and Tuberculosis.
    - Jesus Film Scripts, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Titles: Script in Tibetan with dark blue cover; Tibetan-English Script for the Jesus Film; Script containing English text, references, cues, and syllables with a light blue cover
    - Language Materials - 1, 1960-2003 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Titles: Medical Vocabulary by Basil Gould and Hugh Edward RIchardson (1960); How to Make Tibetan Sounds by Tsultrim Gyatso and Rosie Sleactor (2003); The Use of Tibetan Writing Conventions in Mugom by Daniel P. Watters (2002); Tibetan Spiritual Vocabulary (1997); A Preliminary Sociolinguistic Study of Tibetan Dialects by Lynn Moore, Lois Varenkamp, and Brian Varenkamp (1992)
    - Language Materials - 2, c.a.1919, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Titles: Tibetan Language by C. A. Bell (c.a.1919); A Beginning Textbook of Lhasa Tibetan by Ellen Bartee and Nyima Droma (2000)
    - Language Materials - 3, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Titles: Elementary English in Tibetan by Sandra Benson and Karl Peet (n.d.); Kham Tibetan - English: Colloquial Phrase Book by Judith Rygaard Nielsen (1997)
    - Language Materials - 4, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Titles: An English - Tibetan Dictionary of Key Spiritual Terms (1984)
    - Language Materials - 5, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Titles: Tibetan Spiritual Vocabulary (Syllabus A) (1984); Tibetan Spiritual Vocabulary (1984)
    - Missionary Information - 1, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Titles: By Faith the Gospel Goes to Tibet (n.d.); Christian Missionaries and Tibet (n.d.)
    - Missionary Information - 2, 1901 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Titles: With the Tibetans in Tent and Temple: Narrative of Four Years' Residence on the Tibetan Border, and of a Journey into the Far Interior by Susie Carson Rijnhart (1901)
    - Women, 1975-1997 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Titles: Among Tibetan Women: Tibetan Practices Related to Birth and Name Giving (n.d.); Tibetan Birth Ceremonies by Thupten Sangay (1975); The Universal Childbirth Picture Book by the KunDe Foundation (1997)
  - Nepal Materials
    - Articles, 1999, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Titles: Ethnographical Study of the Church in Syabru, Nepal by Krishna Gurung (1999); The Oppression/Emancipation Nexus in Ongoing Power Struggles: Village-Power Dynamics in Western Nepal by Katsuhiko Masaki (2006)
    - Education, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Titles: Picture Bible: He Lived Among Us (n.d.) - 2 copies
    - Education - 2, 1992 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
      Titles: Picture book with a green cover published by Gospel Recordings Nepal (1992)